NAA History Committee Oral History Interview Transcripts 6004 OHT
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
NAA History Committee Oral History Interview Transcripts
1977-2009
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
National Academy of Arbitrators (NAA)
6004 OHT
2.22 cubic feet
2.2 linear ft.
Transcripts, audiovisual materials.
This collection consists of oral history interview transcripts.
9324245
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, March 01, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 30, 2015
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of oral history interview transcripts.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5246: NAA Records 5775: NAA Records 5796: NAA Additional Records 6004: NAA Additional Records 6004 AV: NAA Audio-Visual Material 6004 OHM: NAA History Committee Oral History Interview Masters 6204: NAA Restricted Committee Files 6205: NAA Committee Files 6136: Dennis Nolan Collection of National Academy of Arbitrators History Files
Industrial relations; Arbitration, Industrial; Collective labor agreements; Mediation and conciliation, Industrial; Aaron, Benjamin; Abernethy, Byron R.; Alexander, Gabriel; Anderson, Arvid; Bairstow, Frances; Block, Howard; Block, Richard; Dash, G. Allen; Dunsford, John E.; Dybeck, Alfred C.; Elson, Alex; Fallon, William J.; Feller, David; Fleming, Robben; Garrett, Sylvester; Gershenfeld, Gladys; Gershenfeld, Walter; Gill, Lewis; Gruenberg, Gladys W.; Harkless, James; Jones, Dallas; Jones, Edgar A.; Kagel, John; Kagel, Sam; Kahn, Mark L.; Kelliher, Peter M.; Killingsworth, Charles C.; Larkin, John Day; Luskin, Bert L.; McDermott, Clare B.; McKelvey, Jean T.(Jean Trepp), 1908-1998.; Mittenthal, Richard; Murphy, William; Nicolau, George; Platt, Harry H.; Robbins, Eva; Roberts, Thomas T.; Rock, Eli; Rubin, Milton; Seward, Ralph T. (Ralph Theodore), 1907-; Sherman, James; Sherman, Marilyn; Simkin, William E.; Sinicropi, Anthony; Smith, Russel A.; St. Antoine, Theodore J., 1929-; Stark, Arthur; Valtin, Rolf; Zack, Arnold; National Academy of Arbitrators; National Academy of Arbitrators. History Committee.
9324245
- NAA. History Committee. Correspondence., 1986-1990 (Box 25, Folder 1)
- NAA. History Committee. Correspondence., 1990-1992 (Box 25, Folder 2)
- NAA. History Committee. Correspondence., 1992-1996 (Box 25, Folder 3)
- NAA. History Committee. Correspondence. Interviewing Projects., 1990-1992 (Box 25, Folder 4)
- NAA. History Committee. Correspondence. Transcripts., 1992-1993 (Box 25, Folder 5)
- Documents Given to NAA Members/Guests on a Tour in May 2007. (Box 25, Folder 6)
- Aaron, Benjamin. Interview Transcript., 1989 (Box 25, Folder 7)
- Abernethy, Byron R. Interview Transcript., 1989 (Box 25, Folder 8)
- Alexander, Gabriel. Interview Transcript., 1989 (Box 25, Folder 9)
- Anderson, Arvid. Interview Transcript., 1989 (Box 25, Folder 10)
- Bairstow, Frances. Interview Transcript., 1994 (Box 25, Folder 11)
- Barrett, Phyllis (wife of Gerald Barrett). Interview Transcript., 2009 (Box 25, Folder 12)
- Bloch, Richard. Interview Transcript., 1996 (Box 25, Folder 13)
- Block, Howard. Interview Transcript., 1993 (Box 25, Folder 14)
- Cole, Howard. David Wolff Rememberances. Interview Transcript., 2009 (Box 25, Folder 15)
- Dash, G. Allen, Jr. Interview Transcript., 1978 (Box 25, Folder 16)
- Dash, G. Allen. Interview Transcript., 1989 (Box 25, Folder 17)
- Dunsford, John E. Interview Transcript., 1989 (Box 25, Folder 18)
- Dybeck, Alfred C. Interview Transcript., 1991 (Box 25, Folder 19)
- Elson, Alex. Interview Transcript., 1993 (Box 25, Folder 20)
- Fallon, William J. Interview Transcript., 1989 (Box 25, Folder 21)
- Feller, David. Interview Transcript., 1994 (Box 25, Folder 22)
- Fleishli, George R. Interview Transcript., 2009 (Box 25, Folder 23)
- Fleming, Robben. Interview Transcript., 2005 (Box 25, Folder 24)
- Garrett, Sylvester. Interview Transcript., 1989 (Box 25, Folder 25)
- Garrett, Sylvester. Interview Transcript., 1980-1989 (Box 25, Folder 26)
  Scope and Contents
  two transcripts. One 1980, one 1989
- Gershenfeld, Gladys. Interview Transcript., 1994 (Box 25, Folder 27)
- Gershenfeld, Gladys. Interview Transcript., 1994 (Box 25, Folder 28)
- Gershenfeld, Walter J. Interview Transcript., 1994 (Box 25, Folder 29)
- Gershenfeld, Walter J. Interview Transcript., 1994 (Box 25, Folder 30)
- Gill, Lewis M. Interview Transcript., 1990 (Box 25, Folder 31)
- Gruenberg, Gladys. Father Brown Memorial Dedication., 1981 (Box 25, Folder 32)
- Gruenberg, Gladys. Interview Transcript., 2006 (Box 25, Folder 33)
- Harkless, James. Interview Transcript., 1995 (Box 25.1, Folder 1)
- Harkless, James. Interview Transcript., 1996 (Box 25.1, Folder 2)
- Harkless, James. Interview Transcript., 2006 (Box 25.1, Folder 3)
- Holley, Jr., William H. Interview Transcript., 2008 (Box 25.1, Folder 4)
- Jones, Dallas. Interview Transcript. (Box 25.1, Folder 5)
  One transcript, no date
- Jones Jr., Edgar A. Interview Transcript., 1989 (Box 25.1, Folder 6)
- Kagel, John. Interview Transcript., 2007 (Box 25.1, Folder 7)
- Kagel, Sam. Interview Transcript., 2005 (Box 25.1, Folder 8)
- Kahn, Mark L. Interview Transcript., 1989 (Box 25.1, Folder 9)
- Kelliher, Peter M. Interview Transcript., 1989 (Box 25.1, Folder 10)
- Kheel, Theodore W. Interview Transcript., 2006 (Box 25.1, Folder 11)
- Killingsworth, Charles C. Interview Transcript., 1989 (Box 25.1, Folder 12)
- Larkin, John Day. Interview Transcript., 1980 (Box 25.1, Folder 13)
- Larney, George. David L. Cole Remembrances. Interview Transcript., 2009 (Box 25.1, Folder 14)
- Luskin, Bert L. Interview Transcript., 1989 (Box 25.1, Folder 15)
- Murphy, William P. Interview Transcript., 1989 (Box 25.1, Folder 16)
- Mittenthal, Richard. Interview Transcript., 1989 (Box 25.1, Folder 17)
- Mittenthal, Richard. Interview Transcript. Miller, David. Rememberances., 2009 (Box 25.1, Folder 18)
- McDermott, Clare B. Interview Transcript., 1989 (Box 25.1, Folder 19)
- McKelvey, Jean T. Interview Transcript., 1989 (Box 25.1, Folder 20)
- Nicolau, George. Interview Transcript., 2006 (Box 25.1, Folder 21)
- Nolan, Dennis. Interview Transcript., 2009 (Box 25.1, Folder 22)
- Platt, Harry H., 1980 (Box 25.1, Folder 23)
- Robbins, Eva. Interview Transcript., 1989 (Box 25.1, Folder 24)
- Roberts, Thomas T. Interview Transcript., 1990 (Box 25.1, Folder 25)
- Rock, Eli. Interview Transcript., 1989 (Box 25.1, Folder 26)
- Rubin, Milton. Interview Transcript., 2007 (Box 25.1, Folder 27)
- Seward, Ralph T. Interview Transcript. (Box 25.1, Folder 28)
- Seward, Ralph T. Interview Transcript., 1977 (Box 25.1, Folder 29)
  Two transcripts. One no date, one 1977
- Sherman, James and Marilyn "Fritzi" Sherman. Interview Transcript., 2007 (Box 25.1, Folder 30)
- Simkin, William E. Interview Transcript., 1977 (Box 25.1, Folder 31)
- Simkin, William E. Interview Transcript., 1989 (Box 25.1, Folder 32)
- Simkin, William E. Interview Transcript., 1989 (Box 25.1, Folder 33)
- Sinicropi, Anthony. Interview Transcript., 1993 (Box 25.1, Folder 34)
- Valtin, Rolf. Interview Transcript. Barrett, Gerald Rememberances., 2009 (Box 25.1, Folder 35)
- Valtin, Rolf. Interview Transcript. Hill, James Rememberances., 2009 (Box 25.1, Folder 35)
- Valtin, Rolf. Interview Transcript. Cole, David Rememberances., 2009 (Box 25.1, Folder 35)
- Valtin, Rolf. Interview Transcript., 1989 (Box 25.1, Folder 35)
- Smith, Russel A. Interview Transcript., 1990 (Box 25.1, Folder 35)
- Stark, Arthur. Interview Transcript., 1989 (Box 25.1, Folder 35)
- St. Antoine, Theodore J. Interview Transcript., 2006 (Box 25.1, Folder 35)
- Valtin, Rolf. Interview Transcript. Guthrie, Paul Rememberances., 2009 (Box 25.1, Folder 35)
- Valtin, Rolf. Interview Transcript. Miller, David Rememberances., 2009 (Box 25.1, Folder 36)
- Valtin, Rolf. Interview Transcript. Murphy, William Rememberances., 2009 (Box 25.1, Folder 37)
- Valtin, Rolf. Interview Transcript. Wallen, Saul Rememberances., 2009 (Box 25.1, Folder 38)
- Valtin, Rolf. Interview Transcript. Woods, H. D. Rememberances., 2009 (Box 25.1, Folder 39)
- Weatherill, J. F. W., 2006 (Box 25.1, Folder 40)
- Zack, Arnold. Interview Transcript., 1993 (Box 25.1, Folder 41)
- Zack, Arnold. Interview Transcript., 2006 (Box 25.1, Folder 42)
- Zack, Arnold. Saul Wallen as Remembered by Arnold Zack., 2009 (Box 25.1, Folder 43)
- NAA Oral Histories (Box 26)
  - Byron R. Abernethy Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    October 27, 1989. Gladys W. Gruenberg, interviewer. Microsoft Word document: ABERNETH.doc
  - Arvid Anderson Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    May 30, 1989. Gerry L. Fellman, interviewer. Microsoft Word document: ANDERSO.doc
  - John E. Dunsford Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    May 31, 1989. William S. Rule, interviewer. Microsoft Word document: DUNSFOR.doc
  - Alfred C. Dybeck Interview Transcript, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    November 2, 1991. Shyam Das, interviewer. Microsoft Word document: DYBECK.doc
  - William J. Fallon Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    May 30, 1989. James L. Stern, interviewer. Microsoft Word document: FALLON.doc
  - Sylvester Garrett Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    June 2, 1989. Gladys W. Gruenberg, interviewer. Microsoft Word document: GARRETT.doc
  - Lewis M. Gill Interview Transcript, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    August 29, 1990. Jim McDonald, interviewer. Microsoft Word document: GILL.doc
  - James M. Harkless Interview Transcript, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    November 10, 1995. Clara H. Friedman, interviewer. Microsoft Word document: HARKNESS.doc
  - Edgar A. Jones, Jr. Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    May 28, 1989. William S. Rule, Interviewer. Microsoft Word document: JONES.doc
  - Mark L. Kahn Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    May 29, 1989. Dennis R. Nolan, interviewer. Microsoft Word document: KAHN.doc
  - Peter M. Kelliher Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    May 30, 1989. James Stern, interviewer. Microsoft Word document: KELLIHER.doc
  - Charles C. Killingsworth Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    May 29, 1989. Dennis R. Nolan, interviewer. Microsoft Word document: KILINGS.doc
  - Bert Luskin Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    May 30, 1989. James Stern, interviewer. Microsoft Word document: LUSKIN.doc
  - Clare (Mickey) McDermott Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    June 1, 1989. Gladys W. Gruenberg, interviewer. Microsoft Word document: MCDERMOT.doc
  - Jean T. McKelvey Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    May 31, 1989. Marian Kincaid Warns, interviewer. Microsoft Word document: MCKELVEY.doc
  - Richard Mittenthal Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    June 2, 1989. Robert G. Williams, interviewer. Microsoft Word document: MITTENTH.doc
  - William P. Murphy Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    May 31, 1989. Marian Kincaid Warns, interviewer. Microsoft Word document: MURPHY.doc
  - Thomas T. Roberts Interview Transcript, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    October 2, 1990. Leo Weiss, interviewer. Microsoft Word document: ROBERTS.doc
  - Eva Robins Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    May 31, 1989. Marian Kincaid Warns, interviewer. Microsoft Word document: ROBINS.doc
  - Eli Rock Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    June 1, 1989. Gerry L. Fellman, interviewer. Microsoft Word document: ROCK.doc
  - Russell Smith Interview Transcript, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    November 30, 1990. Arvid Anderson, interviewer. Microsoft Word document: SMITH.doc
  - Arthur Stark Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    May 29, 1989. Dennis R. Nolan, interviewer. Microsoft Word document: STARK.doc
  - Rolf Valtin Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    May 31, 1989. William S. Rule, interviewer. Microsoft Word document: VALTIN.doc
- NAA Oral Histories (Box 27)
  - Byron R. Abernethy Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Arvid Anderson Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - John E. Dunsford Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Alfred C. Dybeck Interview Transcript, 1991 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - William J. Fallon Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Sylvester Garrett Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Lewis M. Gill Interview Transcript, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - James M. Harkless Interview Transcript, 1995 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Edgar A. Jones, Jr. Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Mark L. Kahn Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Peter M. Kelliher Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Charles C. Killingsworth Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Bert Luskin Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Clare (Mickey) McDermott Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Jean T. McKelvey Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Richard Mittenthal Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - William P. Murphy Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Thomas T. Roberts Interview Transcript, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Eva Robins Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Eli Rock Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Russell Smith Interview Transcript, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Arthur Stark Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Rolf Valtin Interview Transcript, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 23)